[grand orchestral fanfare playing]
- [birds chirping]
- [insects trilling]
[bird squawks]
[monkeys chattering]
[low, deep rumbling]
- [monkey squawks]
- [leaves rustling]
[rumbling grows louder]
[monkey screeches]
[scientist 1] Let me run
the new sequencing.
I'll need a few minutes.
[radio static crackles]
How many times
are we going to keep doing this?
[scientist 2] We keep running it
until the hybrid holds.
[announcer 1 on PA]
We are on security level five.
[scientist 1] The deregs took.
No sign of rejection.
There's still mutations in genome seven.
Thank you.
[announcer 1 on PA]
All genetic waste must be taken
to the cremation chamber by 5:00 p. m.
[announcer 2 on PA] Tank 12 is offline
until genetic modification stabilizes.
All right. Let's get this over with.
Here we go.
Oh. Yeah, sorry. Hold on.
Okay. Yeah.
[keypad beeping]
Three, two, one.
[scientist 3] Step up here.
Waiting for authorization.
[scientist 4 sighs]
I didn't see the labs, but I assume
we upped the soporifics?
[door buzzes]
Yeah. I'm gonna have to go as high
as.5 millimeters per 100 pounds.
[scientist 3] Okay, guys, you're clear.
Well, we don't wanna kill the thing.
Some days I do.
[sighs]
Oh, God.
[announcer 2 on PA] Tank 12 is offline
until genetic modification stabilizes.
[air whooshing]
[crackling]
[powers down]
[computer alarm beeping quietly]
[alarm stops]
[mechanical clanking]
[automated voice]
Alert. Containment failure.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Alert. Containment failure.
[low growling]
Alert. Containment failure.
[deep guttural clicking]
Oh, God. It's loose!
- [alarm blaring]
- [urgent chattering]
[scientist 5] Run!
Containment is locking down!
- Go, go!
- The D-Rex broke free!
Clear the building!
[scientist 6] Seal the doors!
Seal the doors!
- [screams]
- Let's go.
We gotta get out of here.
Come on. Go, go, go!
- DeSantos! The door!
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, no! No, no, no!
- Come on! No.
- No, no, no! No!
- Okay, it just... it won't work...
- It's okay.
- Come on. Come on!
- Okay.
Three, two, one.
[breath trembles]
Come on! Three, two...
- Come on!
- [gasps softly]
[deep growling]
Come on! Open the door! Please!
[heavy footstep booms]
[growling]
Please.
[whispering] Okay, just turn the key.
It's fine. It's okay. Just turn the key.
- Just turn... Just please open the door.
- I'm sorry.
[crying] Please open the door for me.
- [screams]
- No!
- [whimpering]
- [roaring]
[crying] Oh, God! No.
[pained screaming]
[roaring]
[crying] Oh, no! I'm sorry!
[screaming] Oh, no!
[dramatic music playing]
[horns honking]
[driver 1] Come on, what is this?
[driver 2] These things were supposed
to be completely cleared two years ago.
[officer] Yeah, well, I'm not happy
about it either, ma'am.
They're trying to get him up right now.
I don't know what you want me to tell you.
This is where we're at.
[driver 3] What does the mayor do?
Sit on his ass all day?
[officer] It weighs 40 tons, buddy.
Do you want to move it?
[on radio] ♪ Twelve o'clock radio ♪
[radio host]... out of Manhattan.
The cause of the jam
is none other than Bronto Billy,
thought to be the last surviving sauropod
in North America.
- Back to you, Bob.
- Thanks, Hailey.
So, yeah, the aging Brachiosaur,
known to be in poor health,
broke out of
the Cobble Hill Park enclosure
where it had been living
while receiving medical attention.
- [dinosaur bellowing]
- [horns honking]
[chattering]
[worker] Gonna need a bigger crane!
Oh, for God's sake.
Rest in peace already,
but get the hell out of the way.
Damn, that's cold.
Geez!
I mean, even for New York,
it's pretty cold.
[scoffs]
Miss Bennett, I presume?
Hello.
Weren't we supposed to meet at the...
You're not exactly hard to follow.
So, how did you hear about me?
- Paulo Pasolini, Blackwater.
- Mm-hmm.
Does he have a message for me?
Yes. He said to say,
"Felix isn't himself today."
Oh. Okay, I'm listening.
Is that some spy stuff?
'Cause that is fantastic.
What is it that you do at ParkerGenix?
My company is developing a new medication
and we have certain... needs.
Uh-huh. That sounds vague.
And what does that mean in this case?
They say you're good at procuring things
and not asking a lot of questions.
[chuckles] Do they?
They also say you're untroubled
by possible legal or ethical implications.
Well, they need to shut up.
Well, take it as a compliment.
Means you get the job done.
I lost a friend on my last job,
- so I am not up for procurement.
- Well, you don't know what it is yet.
Yes, but you work for
a pharmaceutical company, right? So...
You called me.
I'm spec ops, so it's covert.
I'm guessing info theft.
I'm sorry, I do retrieval
and extractions, not heists.
It's dinosaurs.
They may be through with us,
but we're not through with them.
Well, they are all...
They're all dead or dying, so...
Except for on a few islands
around the equator.
Yes, and those are no-go zones
for a reason.
You go there, you die.
Which is where you come in.
Oh. [chuckles]
No, thanks.
- Ms. Bennett!
- [scoffs]
Did you know that 20% of the world's
population will die of heart disease?
That's one in every five people
on the planet.
Now, just imagine.
Take somebody you know, anybody,
and imagine that you could be the one
to give them an extra 20 years of life.
That's very touching. It's not my field.
And we have very deep pockets.
How deep?
For you, extremely.
Well...
I'm gonna need a number.
Ten, six zeros.
Including the one that's in the ten?
No.
It's a fortune, Ms. Bennett.
The kind of money that would mean
you'd never have to put your life
on the line ever again.
[chuckling]
All right, what's the hitch?
Uh... [clears throat]
Possible criminal charges.
We are going to a place where
every government on the planet
has outlawed travel.
Well, we better not tell anyone, then.
Yeah, that might be a problem.
He doesn't know it yet,
but we're bringing a civilian.
[dramatic orchestral music playing]
- [music continues]
- [dinosaur grunts]
[narrator] The Neo-Jurassic Age
has proven lethal to Dinosauria.
Though some species can survive
in a few isolated oxygen-rich
tropical microclimates
clustered in equatorial regions,
where interactions with humans
and other incompatible modern species...
[worker] Banner coming down.
- Okay, so this is the left metacarpal?
- Yeah.
Ah. Good morning, Doctor.
Sorry to drop in unannounced.
Can we have a word?
Sorry, it's a hell of a day here.
They're closing us down.
Dr. Henry Loomis, Zora Bennett,
- our mission specialist.
- Hello.
Sorry, what mission?
Uh, guys, why don't you just take
a break for a minute, okay?
[chuckles]
Thanks, guys.
Dr. Loomis has been advising ParkerGenix
for the past six months
on paleo-coronary health.
We're developing a new drug, Paleodioxin,
derived from the largest
dinosaur species on record.
Computer modeling suggests
it could forestall coronary disease
by an average of two decades.
Just think what that might have meant
for your mother.
- I'm so sorry for your loss.
- [chuckles]
Okay, anybody can read a file.
If you get personal, though, I'm out.
I'm sorry for overstepping.
This research is crucial.
We just can't get it to trial.
We're unable to synthesize the DNA,
so we need samples from living dinosaurs.
And the species must be a true colossus.
It's the biggest animals
across three categories:
seagoing, land based, and avian.
Why the biggest?
It's their hearts.
The bigger they were,
the bigger their coronary muscles.
And they lived the longest,
over a hundred years
for some Cretaceous-era sauropods.
Which means, the three
dinosaurs they need are...
Mosasaurus,
which lives in the ocean.
And Titanosaurus.
You'll find them on land.
And in the sky,
Quetzalcoatlus.
It's the largest pterosaur.
Each of them had an average lifespan
of well over a century,
- even before DNA refinement.
- [Zora] Mmm.
A drug that could prevent heart disease
would be the biggest medical breakthrough
in centuries.
Yeah, and I'm sure
it'd be worth billions, right?
Trillions.
The only way for our scientists
to complete the strands now
is with blood and tissue samples
from living dinosaurs.
Wait. You wanna take blood samples
from these animals while they're alive?
Hemoglobin deoxygenates
within seconds postmortem.
Lividity and hypostasis
follow immediately.
Fortunately for us, all these species
exist in one isolated location.
We're putting together a team,
and we'd like to leave immediately.
We have competitors, and Mr. Parker
does not tolerate second place.
Can you be ready tomorrow?
Dr. Loomis?
I thought I was just advising.
You are. In person.
We're not qualified to identify
the animals or predict behavior.
Well... [chuckles]
Why don't you send an army?
- You're a rich company.
- Confidentiality.
The fewer people know about this,
the better.
Well, I can guarantee your safety.
I mean, you know, more or less.
No, no, no. It's not about
my safety. It's just...
- "More or less?"
- Yeah.
[quietly] What you're proposing
is really illegal.
Did you tell him about the zeros?
- That's not gonna work with him.
- What are you talking about?
[scoffs]
You ever seen a dinosaur in the wild?
I don't mean in a theme park
when you were a kid
or watching some poor creature
wander around town, lost.
I mean in its natural habitat.
'Cause until you've done that,
you're just a guy who visits zoos.
[sighs]
We sold a dozen tickets all last week.
Five years ago,
you'd have to wait in line for hours,
if you could even get in.
[sighs]
Nobody cares about these animals anymore.
They deserve better.
I just... I need a second.
No, yeah. Take all the time that you need.
Take all the minutes. Not like...
[Krebs sighs]
...your entire life has been,
you know, leading up to this moment.
- [Krebs clears throat]
- [mint crunching]
[crunching continues]
- You ready?
- Yeah.
[sweeping music playing]
[excited chattering]
[cheering]
[sighs]
["Movin' on Up" playing]
[lively chattering in native language]
[groans]
[cheering]
- Three in a row! [laughs]
- [excited chattering]
[Krebs] Captain Kincaid.
Martin Krebs. We spoke on the phone.
Yeah, Krebs, look, I'm sorry.
I thought it over, and I can't do it.
I'd like to, just as a favor
to Zora, but I can't.
[laughs]
What?
We already agreed on the phone.
You named your price.
It's not that. I just...
It's a little too risky for my boat.
She's not paid off yet,
so I imagine you understand.
No hard feelings, Z.
- Hey. Two double rums. Merci.
- [chirping]
What the hell is this? He's your guy.
Yeah. We spent ten years
in MARSOC together.
Duncan's the best,
otherwise I wouldn't be here.
Best at what? Drinking?
- Fabrice, not the guns, okay?
- All right. Okay.
Moving things and people
in and out of places they shouldn't be.
Trouble is, I really can't do it
this time, Z. I'm sorry.
And I'm afraid that's final.
What do you mean?
That's a hell of a setback, Duncan.
You promised me.
But we're screwed now.
I'm sorry.
I hate to see this all fall apart on you.
[sighs]
I'll tell you what.
Why don't you make some
sort of good faith gesture?
Like, maybe, you know,
I'm just spitballing here,
but maybe you could double the number
that you and I spoke about,
and then I can take care of Duncan
and his crew out of my end.
[Krebs] Oh, I see.
[chuckles] That's very nice.
You guys cook this up
on the phone or just now?
I'm just trying to help you out.
I don't have to sit here and be insulted.
For God sakes, fine. Agreed.
Great.
Great. [sighs]
We'll loop up toward Barbados
to avoid government patrols,
but there aren't many anyway.
Why's that?
[laughing]
No one's dumb enough
to go where we're going.
[kids chattering, laughing]
Hey!
Hey! Come here! Oh!
[dinosaur grunting on TV]
[laughing]
- Hey. Over here.
- Hey.
- Hey, Z.
- Hi.
- Hey. How you been?
- Good.
Bobby Atwater.
He'll be helping with team security.
Security for?
Make sure you don't end up
in one of these.
A live one.
Is there anything else?
Yeah, listen, I'm not gonna
be able to do this, you know?
I would love to
as a favor for you, Z, but...
- Oh, no, we ran it already.
- All right, cool.
So, when we leaving?
[sweeping music playing]
- [boat mate] Hey, LeClerc.
- What?
Did you see how much Kincaid's
paying us for this one?
- [laughing] Oh, yeah.
- [laughs]
- We're in trouble.
- Hell, yeah.
[radio beeps]
[static, distorted chatter over radio]
[Krebs] Well, the good news is,
the Mosasaur was tagged in captivity,
and InGen continued
to track it after its escape.
We bought their data
when they entered chapter 11.
So, now, we track it.
Nobody else seems to know much about it,
but that's it right there.
So first sample in 150 miles or so.
Very close to the equator.
But why near the equator?
Why don't they survive anywhere else?
The fitness landscape of the Earth
no longer suits them.
The air is different.
Uh, the solar radiation is different,
the insects, vegetation.
Everything is different.
But close to the equator, it's nearly
the climate of 60 million years ago.
It's warmer and rich with oxygen.
And the Mosasaur generally
circles the island we're headed to.
There's a complex there
that was R and D for the original park.
It was abandoned after an accident.
We're gonna wanna get in,
get our three samples,
and get out as quickly as possible.
Because even though two dozen species
have survived there, alone,
for almost 20 years,
make no mistake, this is by no means
a controlled environment.
[Atwater chuckles]
Yeah, I think we'll be okay.
What are those?
[Atwater] Neurotoxins.
[Zora] How fast?
[Atwater] Paralysis
within a couple of seconds.
And then what?
And then you survive.
Is this the part where you, uh, tell me
it's a crime to kill a dinosaur, Doctor?
No, this is where I tell you
it's a sin to kill a dinosaur.
[chuckling]
And so, uh, what if it's us or them, hmm?
Then we've put ourselves in a place
where we don't belong.
[scoffs]
Hmm. That's kind of
our specialty, Dr. Loomis.
We have no intention
of harming the animals.
Let's just get our samples and go home.
Gonna lose the light
before we make contact.
We'll make a run
first thing in the morning.
How does extraction work?
[Loomis] These darts
collect blood samples.
You get one shot with each.
The Mosa has four inches of hide, so you
must be within ten meters to penetrate.
And it self-ejects
when it reaches capacity.
[dart beeping]
It should fire a couple of hundred feet
in the air, like a model rocket.
On the day, a parachute will open,
and it'll float back down to us.
I'll take the shot.
Uh, remote biopsy darting is pretty basic.
I'm sure I can handle it.
Oh.
[laughing]
Let me show you something.
- You feel that spray?
- Yeah.
Now imagine the boat rocking
at 15 to 20 degrees,
we're moving at 30 knots,
you got sweat running in your eyes,
and you're close enough
to look that thing right in the teeth.
You got this.
Uh, please, be my guest.
Oh, really? If you insist.
[chuckling]
[chuckling continues] I can't take it.
[radio beeping]
- It's been fun working with you, Z.
- What?
But I think we just found
our new team leader.
[laughing]
No offense.
I mean, I don't know anybody
that could be offended by that.
That's mean.
Oh.
I heard about Booker.
[inhales deeply, sighs]
Yeah.
I'm so sorry.
What job were you on?
[sighs] Um, just a simple
training mission in Yemen.
Couldn't have been more basic.
Just a car bomb.
Out of nowhere.
Quick at least.
Not really.
Ah, shit.
He didn't deserve that.
No.
[sighs]
I had to tell his wife. It was brutal.
- You can't keep this up forever, Z.
- No.
This work.
It breaks you eventually.
What do you think I'm doing down here?
I'm just trying to, you know,
buy my life back.
Really? I thought you just missed me.
- Well.
- [chuckles]
- You know what I actually missed?
- Mmm.
My own mother's funeral.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
That's terrible, Zora.
Yeah. Yeah.
No, seriously. That's like the worst thing
I've ever heard anybody do.
Thank you. That's so supportive of you.
Oh.
God.
Please tell me
you worked it out with Amelia.
Well.
Whenever we looked at each other, we just...
just saw our little boy.
Easier for us both just to
go at it alone, you know?
We are very pathetic.
All right, what do you say we stay alive?
And, uh, you know,
get rich this time.
Rich is nice, but it won't be enough.
For sure.
Do something that matters
while there's still time.
Okay.
Don't just brush that off. I mean it.
Don't wait, Zora.
Do not wait.
[sighs]
["Harmony Hall" playing]
♪ We took a vow in summertime ♪
♪ Now we find ourselves
In late December... ♪
You're rationing those, honey?
I'm enjoying them.
[sighs, grunts] Honey,
it's a long way across the Atlantic.
You're gonna miss 'em when you run out.
Can I ask why you have
so many in your pocket?
So he doesn't eat them.
Ah, right.
Hey, honey. Where's your boyfriend?
It's his turn at the wheel.
- Is he coming or what?
- I told him.
He's just getting dressed.
Okay.
[sighs] Okay. Do you wanna practice?
All right.
Remember, okay,
it's just like Dad showed you.
Under, under, around.
You guys ever wish you had a boring dad?
- We do.
- Yeah.
[chuckling]
[boyfriend] Ah.
Finally.
- Good evening, Xavier.
- Ah, what's up?
Six o'clock.
[laughs] I know.
I was out cold.
It's your watch.
I slept like a baby.
You-You've got the wheel?
Man, I am so tired.
I'm gonna be honest.
I'd probably conk out at the wheel.
I'll take his shift. It's fine.
No, no, no, honey,
we've been through this.
You need sleep. I need sleep.
It's your shift, Xavier. Come on, man.
Reuben, can't we just anchor, for once?
We can use the anchor.
We haven't done that yet.
We only carry 50 meters of anchor chain.
It's 2,000 meters to the bottom.
[Xavier] Oh.
Kinda sounds like somebody should've
thought about that before we left.
Do you have any idea
the weight of two thou...
I built this boat, okay, Xavier?
I know what I'm doing.
So you're good? You're good on the wheel.
You know what?
Just grab another hour. I'm fine.
- Yes. Perfect. You're the best.
- I got it. I'm fine.
Fist bump? Give me some.
Never mind. [grunts]
Oh, you got licorice, dude?
I love this stuff.
I didn't say a word. Not-Not one word.
Good.
So don't.
What... Did he even bring a shirt?
Okay, clearly, you don't see
the side of him that I see.
The naked side.
Hey! [scoffs]
I mean, I... I guess I'd hoped
it would just be the three of us.
You know, one last hurrah.
I'm going to NYU, not Mongolia.
I know. You're right.
What are those?
Where?
One o'clock. Moving east.
- Dolphins?
- No.
No fins.
Sails.
- [boat rumbling]
- [grunting]
Bella, grab the wheel.
[dramatic music playing]
[grunts, pants]
- Left, left, left.
- [grunts]
[grunting]
Something big sideswiped us.
Sailfish?
Bigger.
Is it the you-know-what?
No, honey, it's not a you-know-what.
There's barely any left.
[Isabella] I hate those things.
I wish they never came back.
I think we should just head ba...
[screaming]
- [dinosaur roaring]
- [all shouting]
[Isabella screaming]
[screaming]
Hold on!
Dad!
- Dad!
- Teresa!
Xavier's inside.
I'll get him. Get to the top!
Get to the top!
[Teresa] Swim!
Xavier!
- It's not opening! Reuben, it won't open.
- Let it fill with water.
Let it fill, then you can open the door.
Get the radio! In the red bag!
The red bag! The emergency bag!
- Get up!
- Okay.
Go!
- Where is it? I can't find it!
- Get it!
It's in the bag, the emergency bag.
The emergency radio.
Okay.
Dad!
[Teresa] Xavier!
Hey! Just get out. [inhales deeply]
[inhales deeply]
Teresa!
Bella! Bella, hold on.
[dinosaur bellowing]
- [Teresa] Xavier!
- [Isabella] Xavier!
- Dad!
Dad!
- Xavier!
- Dad!
- Honey!
Dad!
Where's Xavier?
What happened?
Dad, where is he?
[Reuben] I don't know.
I'll go back down. I'll keep looking.
[Xavier gasping]
Xavier! Xavier!
[bellowing]
Xavier!
Xavier, swim!
Xavier, hurry!
- Swim! Xavier!
- Come on!
[panting]
- Come on! Come on! Come on!
- Swim, Xavier!
Faster! Come on!
- Hurry! Faster!
- Xavier! Come on!
[bellowing]
[grunting]
Dad.
[Xavier] I...
I got the bag.
[thunder rumbling]
["This Girl" playing on stereo]
♪ Money rains... ♪
[chattering in French]
♪ But keep the change
'Cause I've got enough ♪
[both laughing]
- ♪ A little time... ♪
- [song fades]
[door opens]
Am I interrupting?
Oh. No.
It's fine.
I can't sleep. [chuckles]
[chuckles]
Well, they say if you can sleep
the night before,
you should probably quit.
You don't hear that much in museum work.
You wanna sit down?
Can I ask what was bothering you?
Maybe a little PTSD.
I probably should've taken
some more time off after my last job.
What are you?
Like a mercenary?
Situational security and reaction.
So a mercenary, then.
[chuckles]
Well, still, sounds way more exciting
than my life.
Yeah? How exactly?
Well, I have never been shot at.
No?
- Mm-mmm.
- Wow.
Well.
There's still time.
Good night, Doctor.
Good night.
[seagulls calling in distance]
[static crackling]
[Reuben on radio] Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
This is the Mariposa.
Last known position 24... [garbled speech]
[garbled radio chatter continues]
[snoring]
[toy dinosaur roaring]
[gasps]
[in French]
- What's our distance to target?
- [grunts] Ah.
[in French]
Just resting your eyes, huh?
Euh, ouais.
[in French]
Merci.
No French before breakfast.
[garbled radio chatter continues]
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
This is the Mariposa.
We are sinking.
Last known position 24 degrees 33 north
and 74, 56 west.
We are sinking.
[Zora] The signal was clear, right?
I mean, you sure you heard a mayday?
Positive.
But did you get a location?
Down to ten square meters.
They sent a DSC.
Twenty-eight miles away.
Well, that's 28 miles, you know,
in the opposite direction.
What? Bobby, what, do you want
to leave them? Come on.
Nah, of course not.
I'm saying this guy has a working radio.
And, you know,
he can transmit his location.
It's true. It's not as if
they're gonna freeze to death.
I mean, I'm saying, like,
help is gonna be on its way.
There's probably a coast guard ship
on its way right now.
Two miles.
Look, we are three minutes away
from this Mosasaur,
which, may I remind you,
is what we came here for.
The Mosasaur is tagged.
We found it once, we'll find it again.
Maybe we can, but, Z, we're talking about
tens of millions of dollars here.
And all they need to do is just
float around for a couple of hours.
I've got visual.
13 degrees off the port side.
[Loomis] That's it.
Okay, I have to agree with Mr., um...
- Atwater.
- Right.
- The Mosasaur first.
Right?
LeClerc, new course.
24, 33 north, 74, 56 west.
Flank speed.
[LeClerc] Aye aye.
We're search and rescue now.
It's my charter.
It's my boat.
[groans, sighs]
[rummaging in bag]
[hopeful music playing]
[Xavier] Is that... Is that?
- Oh, my God. Hey.
- [Teresa] Oh, my God.
[Xavier] Hey. Hey!
- Hey!
- [Teresa] Hey, over here!
Over here!
[Teresa] I don't know.
It was, like, the size of the boat.
Bigger. 50 feet. 70, I don't know.
It's a snakelike body,
with a large skull and a long snout?
Yes, yes.
- And limbs like paddles?
- Yes, yes.
A long tail region with a downcurved end?
Look, man, that's what it is.
What else could it be?
What the hell you doing this far out
with a little kid?
We're just making a crossing.
Barbados to Cape Town.
We've done it before.
Shouldn't they be in school?
They are. It's summer break.
What is your problem?
My problem is you should've known better.
How? There are 50,000 boats
on this ocean right now.
One was attacked by a Mosasaur.
What are the odds?
Duncan, let it go, okay?
You know you're not pissed off at him.
Okay? These kids are safe now.
All right. I don't understand.
Why would a Mosasaur attack
a 45-foot sailboat? It's not food.
[Loomis] Maybe it thought
the boat was a rival,
and it wanted to eliminate
any competition.
How far off course are we?
Twenty-eight miles.
And how long to reacquire the target?
Uh, two hours, maybe.
Depends how fast it's moving
and in which direction.
Well, what say we turn the boat around
and get the mission back on track.
Wait, wait, wait. How fast what's moving?
What mission?
So... [chuckles] About that. It's, uh...
Okay. So, exactly
what are you guys doing here?
Uh, we are gonna take a detour
and pick up a few items, and that's it.
- What... What items?
- It's okay, honey.
- It's okay.
- What is she talking about?
Hey. That guy...
Hi. Excuse me.
...is creeping me out.
- What'd I do?
- You're creeping me out.
Can we get the tracking map up, please?
All right, look. Look...
we understand
you've got your own business, and...
and, um...
we're very grateful to you.
You pulled us out of the water,
we're not going to forget that,
- but can you just drop us off from...
- Is that it?
- That would be great.
- [Nina] Flip this up.
It's hard to tell.
You can leave us at any convenient port.
Please. Yeah?
The software's ghosting.
It's doubling the signal.
- Maybe it's just echoing off our boat.
- That's not an echo.
- What?
- What is it you need to get?
That's two signals.
[Nina speaking French quietly]
So we already found it?
No, no.
It found us.
[alarm blaring]
- Oh, no, no. Come on, guys.
- [Teresa] Okay...
- [boat rumbling]
- [all gasping]
- [Loomis] It's here.
- [Kincaid] Nina, tell me something.
[Nina] Everything's online. It's fine.
[Teresa] Okay, so we just got away from
it, and you guys have been chasing it?
[Nina] Starboard. Yeah, yeah.
Guys, listen. We're gonna be
a couple of minutes tops.
Then we're all going to this island
like she said, okay?
There's a village complex there
with geothermal energy that still works.
You can wait there.
You'll be totally safe.
- [Xavier] What?
- [Teresa] Oh, my God.
- [Kincaid] There, starboard.
- [Krebs] Okay.
[Zora] Let's go!
- Take the wheel. I'll get a bearing.
- Aye, aye.
[dramatic music playing]
[bellowing]
Ah! It's beautiful!
- [Nina] Yes!
- Whoo!
Let's go!
[bellowing]
We're losing her.
Loomis, I need you
to secure me to the bow rail!
[Loomis] Okay.
[Zora] Make it tight.
- Like this?
- Yeah.
- The other side!
- Okay.
Remember, don't fire
until it's within ten meters.
[Zora] Got it.
All right.
Nina, I need command up here now.
[console beeping]
Comm is yours.
[bellowing]
Come on. Come on!
We gotta be closer. Move it!
Hey. Get up here and spot.
[Nina on radio] On my way.
20 meters.
Almost in range!
- 15 meters.
- Copy.
[groans]
[bellowing]
[grunts]
- Another dart!
- Okay.
Come on!
[Isabella whimpering]
[bellowing]
It's coming at us! Turn! Turn!
Quick! It's in range.
Come on!
There, go!
[roaring]
[Zora grunting]
[growling]
Hey! [grunts]
Help me up. Help me.
[grunting]
[Krebs] Come on!
Take the shot!
[dart beeping]
[laughs]
[shouts]
[panting]
It worked!
Yes! Come down ten knots.
Hard starboard. Down ten. Down ten.
[Nina] Steady.
Portside off the stern rail.
[panting]
[Loomis] I got it! I got it!
[grunts]
Nice shot.
Nice rocket.
That was fantastic.
- Yeah?
- Oh, my God. That was genius.
[chattering in French]
- Yes.
- That was good.
[LeClerc speaking French]
[Loomis] Oh, God.
[excited chatter continues]
Whoo!
[laughter]
[LeClerc speaking French]
[Reuben] Gotta be calm. Just breathe.
- [Loomis] Hey.
- [Zora] Hey.
- [Reuben] It's okay, honey.
- [Isabella] Dad.
- What if we don't?
- [Reuben] It's okay.
What if we don't what?
Well, what if we get the samples,
and we don't give them over
to a company that makes a lifesaving drug
and then prices it so 99% of the planet
can't afford it?
Science is for all of us, not some of us.
Have you thought about that?
No, I guess I haven't.
Well, then maybe you should start.
Maybe you should stop.
- [Xavier hyperventilating]
- [Reuben] Hey, Xavier.
Head between your legs, deep breaths.
Hey. Deep breaths. Deep breaths.
Dad, I think I'm gonna be sick.
It's all right, honey. Just breathe.
[Isabella breathing heavily]
[latches click, case beeps]
Those things from the boat. They're...
They're back.
- Oh, my God.
- [Isabella] Dad.
What the hell are those?
[Reuben] Sit down, honey. Stay close.
Spinosaurus.
Ha-ha! It's mutualism.
Inter-species symbiosis.
Those Spinosaurus?
They help the Mosasaur hunt.
They help it kill!
- Well, that's discouraging.
- [gun cocks]
[dinosaur grunts]
These are our waters now.
[grunts]
[all gasping]
[Kincaid] Over here. There's another one.
[Krebs] There. Seven o'clock.
Hurry! Quick!
[gunfire]
Bobby. Bobby, Bobby, look out!
[roaring]
[screaming]
No!
[straining]
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
Bobby! Bobby, no!
- [panting]
- [Atwater choking]
[roaring]
[both grunting]
[screams]
[grunting, screaming]
- Dad!
- Bella!
[screaming]
- [straining]
- [bone cracks]
[screams]
[whimpering] Dad!
Dad!
[straining] Oh, my God.
What are you doing?
You're heading into the rocks!
I can outrun those things.
The Mosasaur can't go into shallow water.
[bellowing]
[Kincaid] Everybody hold on to something.
[groaning] I can't move my leg, honey.
[crying]
If we hit those rocks, we're gonna wreck.
Tie these to everything you need.
Be ready to jump.
[bellowing]
It's fast.
LeClerc, the engine's overheating.
Teresa, get back inside. Get on the radio.
Mayday three times and send coordinates.
- Go!
- Three times, send coordinates. Got it.
[Reuben] Hang on, honey.
Isabella. Isabella, hey, look at me.
It's gonna be okay. Listen...
[panting]
- Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
- Okay. Hang on.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Is anybody there? Mayday.
- Stop.
- Hey!
- Just stop. Stop for a second.
- What do you mean, "stop"?
We gotta handle this ourselves.
- What?
- This is the protocol.
- Are you crazy?
- Just give me...
No! No, no, no! Hey! Mayday, mayday!
Back off!
[grunts]
[whimpering]
[crying] Please help me!
Please help me! Please!
Please! Please help me!
Grab my hand! Please!
Dad!
[screams]
Sweetie!
Teresa! No!
Teresa!
[grunts]
- [Reuben] Teresa!
- [grunts]
Teresa, no!
[dinosaur bellowing]
Man overboard!
Listen to me.
We're going in the water now.
Yes. The boat's gonna crash.
We have to. Your sister's there.
- You understand? Hey. Hey.
- [whimpering]
Hey. I'm here, okay?
All right? I've got you.
You're all right. Come on! Come on!
Get ready. On the count of three.
One, two...
- Hey!
- Three!
Hey! We need to stick together.
[Loomis] Keep going.
- [bellowing]
- [Nina grunting]
[Zora grunting]
[roaring]
[metal grinding]
Whoa! Get down!
[Zora grunting]
[grunts]
[panting]
- [roaring]
- [engine sputtering]
[both grunt]
Zora. It can't go in the shallows.
Jump. Go! Jump!
[bellowing]
[laughs] Told you!
[shouts]
[shouting]
[seagulls squawking]
[both panting]
[Xavier] I thought I lost you.
Are you okay?
- He let me fall.
- Who?
The guy on the boat. He tried to kill me.
I knew he was creepy!
[Reuben] Teresa. Teresa!
Dad!
- I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Yeah? I got you. I got you. Thank God.
[grunts] You all right? You good?
Let's get out of the water.
[grunting]
[groaning]
[metal creaking]
- [roaring in distance]
- [gasps]
Keep moving! They're amphibious!
[snarling in distance]
[grunting, coughing]
[Kincaid] LeClerc, you okay?
[in French]
[breathing heavily]
[Loomis] Move! Keep going!
[sighs]
[softly] We made it.
- [Loomis] I've got it here.
- Do we still have the case?
[Loomis grunting]
[Zora] You got that side?
- [Loomis] We're getting there. Pull.
- [Zora] Yeah.
- [Nina straining]
- [Loomis] Yeah. Come on. Grab it.
Keep going. Yeah. Go on.
Grab it. Keep moving.
It's all right.
Just keep going to the beach.
[panting]
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
Nina!
Nina! Nina!
Kincaid!
Nina!
[Isabella crying softly]
Hey. Hey. I know. I know.
It's okay, honey.
They said there's a village here.
We'll find it and get help.
All right? You don't feel like talking?
It's okay, honey. You don't have to.
[panting]
You'll be okay.
She'll be okay, right?
Uh, yeah.
[birds chirping, calling]
Oh, wow.
So, like, when an old person buys a bed,
do you think before they buy it,
they look at it and they go,
"Oh, wow, man, this is...
this is my deathbed"?
[animals calling in distance]
[Xavier] Because I'm thinking that...
right now.
I think we got it.
Come on. Let's go find this village.
- Hurry up.
- [roar in distance]
We can't stay here. They'll come back.
- [Krebs] They're more like mutations.
- What do you mean, "mutations"?
Abnormalities, deviations.
I know what the word means.
What does it mean here, where we are?
- [Kincaid] What are you talking about?
- This island that we're on,
Mr. Roarke here didn't tell us everything
that we need to know.
Look, dinosaurs are dinosaurs.
What difference does it make?
Fine. Don't tell us.
We could just leave you here. It's fine.
Fine. So this island was
a laboratory of sorts.
They conducted experimental work here.
What kind of experiments?
Crossbreeding of species.
The theme park owners were just responding
to what the audience wanted.
They were tired of looking
at the same old thing.
"Engineered entertainments,"
they called 'em.
Genetically-altered freaks?
Yeah. And you don't want to do that
in the middle of a theme park, do you?
Ideally, you don't try
weird genetic shit at all.
Well, they learned that the hard way.
Any that were malformed or just
too damn hard for anybody to look at,
they left 'em here.
[animals calling in distance]
[Loomis] But that's inhuman.
Why not just euthanize them?
The average cost of
a created species is 72 million dollars.
What would you do,
kill it and have to tell your bank,
or just carry it forward under R and D?
What would I do with mutant dinosaurs
from an accounting perspective?
Is that really the question?
[roaring in distance]
Can we please just hurry this along?
Everybody, please stay cool.
Our situation hasn't changed.
Two of our friends just died. Clearly,
the situation's changed quite a bit.
Yes, and that's horrible.
But this is where we are now, desperate,
and that's not any different than before.
We were all desperate to begin with,
otherwise we wouldn't have come. Right?
You, you specialize
in a subject nobody cares about anymore.
You're about to be out of a job.
You need this.
I want the money. You want the money.
Your company wants all the money.
We still have that case.
First sample's in it.
Let's get the other two.
[Krebs] That's a great idea.
[Kincaid] We have no weapons, Z.
We never did. I mean, not really.
We had a few toys
that would have made us feel better.
They could have worked or not.
We are where we're supposed to be.
We know what we're supposed to do.
Let's just get what we need and get out.
Those kids, the people that went
into the ocean, they could still be alive.
I say we find them first
and then we get out.
Uh, get out how?
Does anyone wanna hear the backup plan?
[Krebs chuckles] She has a backup plan?
She doesn't get out of bed
without a backup plan.
I hired an exfil team
to monitor our boat's radio frequency.
So if we go silent for 24 hours,
they'll do a flyby at exactly sunset
on the second night.
But that's tomorrow.
Your plans showed a village complex
on the southwest ridge with a helipad.
They'll hover for exactly two minutes.
If no one shows, they'll leave.
- But if they see us...
- Why only two minutes?
Why don't they just land?
Pilots wanna live too.
[Loomis] Oh, great.
We gotta find high ground
before the sun goes down.
[animals calling]
[dinosaur roaring in distance]
We have to go now.
[Zora] Drop anything
you can't carry all day.
[in French]
Just try not to die.
[panting]
[adventurous music playing]
Warm.
There's geothermal power.
Must come through these pipes
from hot springs.
It must lead to the village.
[Teresa grunting]
Maybe there's a radio?
Great. [chuckles] Yeah.
We'll use that to get the guy
who tried to kill me.
Or, you know, to get rescued?
Yeah. Then we'll get the son of a bitch.
Right. Okay, we follow the pipes
to the village.
Unless somebody's got another idea.
I have some weed.
Might be a little damp, but, uh,
I feel like we could just chill here, no?
You don't smoke, you... Do you smoke?
No?
[laughs]
Okay, Dad, he's, uh...
he's clearly messing with you.
Oh.
[chuckles]
- [sighs]
- [Xavier] Yo, help me up?
Funny.
All right. No one help me up. That's fine.
[insects chirring]
[Zora] Maybe that family will know
to head for the village.
[Kincaid] God, I hope so.
[animals calling in distance]
[Zora] How far to the next sample?
Well, according to the satellite imagery,
the Titanosaur herd stays
in the central valley.
We should reach them by dawn.
- [animal chitters]
- [gasps]
Be careful where you step.
Something just moved past my leg.
Hey. You wanna tell me how
the girl fell over the rail?
The thing hit the boat. You were there.
But so were you,
on the bridge, next to her.
So there was nothing you could do?
What are you implying?
This isn't your first expedition, huh?
No, I've been on digs since I was 12.
I studied under Alan Grant as a postdoc.
I suppose you're
in this kind of situation all the time?
[chuckles] Used to be.
I hate the jungle. I try to avoid it now.
Why is that?
You can't see three feet in front of you,
and you always know you're being stalked.
And the only place to hide is underwater.
I refuse to die in the jungle.
My dream is I die in a shallow sea,
and I'm buried quickly by silt.
That's beautiful.
It's the best chance
of being fossilized that way.
[Kincaid laughing]
You're a weirdo.
Thank you.
[Krebs] You gotta drop this.
She screamed,
I turned around, and then she was gone.
[Zora] Okay. All right.
If I find out otherwise, though,
we'll leave you here
and you can rejoin the food chain.
[chuckles] I'm too smart to die.
You know, intelligence is massively
overrated as an adaptive trait.
- Oh, yeah?
- Seriously.
Enlighten us.
Dinosaurs, pretty dumb, right?
And yet they survived
for 167 million years.
And we Homo sapiens,
geniuses by comparison,
only have about 200,000 years so far.
But with our huge cranial cavities,
we're so smart,
we already have
the capacity to annihilate ourselves.
I doubt we make it to even one million.
Hold on. Don't we rule the earth?
We gotta be doing something right.
We don't rule the earth.
We just think we do.
I mean, sure,
we're changing the environment,
but that makes us the ones
to worry about, not the planet.
When the Earth gets tired of us,
believe me,
it will shake us off like a summer cold.
Of all species that have existed on Earth,
99.9% of them are now extinct.
Survival is a long shot.
[sighs]
[water splashing]
Whoa.
You hear that?
Every day could be your last.
All right, everyone, find a stick.
You'll need it to clear your way.
[grunts, gasps]
- [panting]
- [chittering]
[Reuben] Bella?
It's okay.
It's little.
See? And it's a plant-eater.
It's okay.
No. No. Go.
- Go. Shoo.
- [dinosaur whimpering]
- [grunts] Hey, Xavier.
- Yeah.
You jumped in after her.
Yeah.
Respect for that.
[chuckles]
Whatever, guapo.
Hard to like, honey.
Yeah.
Took me a minute, too.
Let's do this.
[grunting]
[dinosaur grumbling]
Let's do this... [stammers]
...but, like, going that way, though.
[Zora] What are the last two species?
Uh, Titanosaur and Quetzalcoatlus.
An 11-ton sauropod
and a pterosaur the size of a school bus
with 30-foot wings.
[Kincaid] One of those little buses
like for field trips, or the full thing?
[Krebs] Does it matter?
[Kincaid] Just asking.
[deep metallic creaking]
[animals chittering, calling]
[dinosaur grumbling softly]
[panting]
[fire crackling softly]
It's okay.
You get some more sleep
while I take it for a while.
Oh, no. I'm okay.
I know you're okay, but it's my watch.
You sure?
Yeah.
[groans] Thanks.
The pipes, they just go right up that way,
hopefully towards the village.
All right?
You know, I was wrong about you.
No, you're right. I'm lazy as hell.
[chuckles]
She might be alive
because of what you did.
I don't even know why
she wants to be with me. [chuckles]
Well, she sees who you are.
Thank God she doesn't.
Hey.
Hey!
Other people may talk shit about us,
but we don't have to do the job for them.
Otherwise it becomes true.
Well, I gotta take a piss.
[breathes deeply]
[dinosaur chittering]
[leaves rustling]
[chittering]
[clicking tongue]
[clicking tongue] Come on.
Come.
It's okay.
Come on. [clicking tongue]
[chuckles softly]
[dinosaur calling in distance]
- [sighs]
- [urinating]
[growling softly]
[exhales]
[spits]
[sniffs]
[hissing]
- [dinosaurs shrieking]
- [urinating stops]
[whimpers]
[shrieking continues]
[slashing, crunching]
- [roars]
- [grunts]
[slashing]
- [breathing heavily]
- [squawks]
[panting]
- [urinating]
- [panting]
[Krebs] How much further?
[Loomis] Not far.
The Titanosaur herd
should be right across this valley.
[Zora] But they're herbivores, right?
[Loomis] Yeah.
[Zora] That's good.
[Loomis] But the things
that hunt them aren't.
[Krebs] Oh, great.
[Kincaid shushing]
[whispers] Quiet.
[dinosaurs breathing slowly]
[dinosaurs continue breathing slowly]
[dinosaur bellowing faintly in distance]
[dinosaurs bellowing faintly in distance]
[bellowing, slow breathing stop]
[mint crunching]
[Zora sighs] Mmm.
You want one? Mmm.
[sighs]
[grass rustling]
[gasps]
[bellowing softly]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh. [chuckles]
- [bellowing]
- [birds chirping]
[panting] What?
[bellowing]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[birds chirping]
You're a secret adrenaline junkie, Henry?
This is our chance. They're distracted.
Distracted by what?
[dinosaur bellowing]
[gasps] Oh.
[panting]
Okay.
[dinosaurs bellowing]
[hopeful music playing]
You don't see that every day.
Or ever.
[breathing shakily]
[sniffling]
[panting]
[bellowing continues]
[purring]
[bellows sharply]
[laughs]
[bellowing]
[chuckles] Whoo!
- [dart beeping]
- [dinosaur grunts]
[sweeping music playing]
[sighs]
[sweeping music continues]
[case beeps]
[dinosaurs squawking in distance]
One to go.
Looks like we're climbing.
[Kincaid] Hope you're good
with heights, Doc.
[Reuben] The guys on the boat
said there was power at the village.
We just have to trust
that they were right.
[Xavier] Hey, how much further
do you think it is?
A mile, maybe two.
[groans, grunts]
Is your leg okay?
Yeah, it just hurts a little. I'm fine.
It's okay.
[dinosaur chittering]
[Teresa] And, uh...
are we okay with... that?
[smacking lips]
It's helping her.
It's okay. I got an eye on it.
[grunting]
Mom's never gonna trust you with us again.
[chuckles] Oh, God, no.
[Isabella] Hey, guys.
I'm naming her Dolores.
[Xavier] Iz, you're alive?
You talk?
I'm taking her home with me.
That may or may not be a terrible idea.
Dolores?
Hey, you good?
Yeah, it's, uh...
It's just kinda nice, you and your dad.
I don't know.
Maybe this whole thing will... [grunting]
Xavier!
[Reuben] Bella, Bella! Bella, wait!
- [Isabella screams]
- [Reuben grunts]
[all grunting]
[dramatic music playing]
- [Xavier grunts]
- [Teresa yelps]
[Reuben groans]
[Isabella yelps]
[all breathing heavily]
[Dolores chittering]
What's the smell?
[chittering]
[Isabella] What's wrong with her?
What is she scared of?
[tense music playing]
[Reuben] Help me up.
[grunts]
[panting]
We'll follow the river that way.
I see a boat.
You can't walk.
Xavier can help you while I go get it.
All right. Be careful.
Can I get some more licorice?
[sighs]
[whimpers]
[tense music playing]
- [insect buzzes]
- [whispers] Oh, my God.
[grunts]
[Reuben whispering] Teresa.
Teresa! Hurry.
Just go. Come on.
[flies buzzing]
[chewing]
[dinosaur grunting]
[chirping]
[hissing, rattling]
Careful.
- [dinosaur shrieks]
- [dinosaur grumbles]
[whimpers]
[squeals]
[panting softly]
[dinosaur breathing slowly]
[grass rustling]
[low growling]
[yawning]
[whispering] Come on. Come on.
- Shh. Don't wake it up.
- Come on. Come on.
[growling softly]
[whispering] Move! Come back.
[panting softly]
Okay.
No.
Shit.
- [high-pitched chittering]
- [gasps]
[Dolores chittering]
[whispering] Dolores!
You have to go. It's not safe.
[snoring]
[whimpers softly]
Please, go, go, go, go, go.
Shoo! Shoo!
[grunting]
Come on. Come on.
[whispering] No. Don't.
No, don't. Don't. Don't.
[air whooshing]
[grunts]
[Reuben] Teresa, come on.
Come on.
Come on, baby. Come on!
Come on!
[grunts]
[dinosaur grunts]
[growling breaths]
[whispering] Come on! Come on!
Okay.
[dinosaur squawking]
[dinosaur grunts]
Isabella.
Come on. Come on.
[dramatic music playing]
[Reuben grunting]
All right, sit in the front now.
- Let's go. Go.
- [bellowing]
[Reuben] Quietly.
- [shouting] Go! Go! Go!
- [Isabella whimpering]
[Teresa] Paddle!
Paddle. Come on.
[Xavier grunting]
- [Isabella] Dad!
- [Reuben] Okay, okay, okay. Okay.
Come on, come on, come on!
[shouting] Paddle, paddle, paddle!
Dad!
- [Teresa] Go!
- [Xavier] Come on. Come on. Come on.
- [Isabella] Go!
- [Reuben] Come on. Come on.
Paddle!
- [grunting]
- [Xavier] Dig, dig!
Dig! Dig! Come on!
Come on, come on, come on.
[Reuben] As hard as you can! Dig! Dig!
Come on! Paddle!
Paddle! Paddle!
[all screaming]
[bellows]
[roaring]
[gasping]
Isabella! Swim! Go! Go!
Bella!
[roaring]
Isabella! [grunts]
[bellows]
[inhales deeply]
[growling]
[roaring]
- Bella!
- Dad!
Keep going.
[roaring]
[Reuben] Come on!
Bella!
- Bella!
Isabella!
[grunting]
[Isabella, muffled] Dad! Dad!
Dad!
Bella! Bella!
- [roaring]
- [Isabella] Dad!
Dad, help!
[whimpering]
Dad!
- No. Isabella!
- Dad!
[grunting]
No! Bella!
- [whimpering]
- [growling]
Dad.
[roaring]
Isabella, no!
[crying] No! No!
- No!
- [whimpering]
[panting]
Bella! Bella, come on. Come on! Swim!
Come on.
[roaring]
Dad!
Bella, swim!
- [Reuben] Come on! I got you!
- Bella, it's coming!
- Come on!
- I got you.
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
[screaming]
[roaring]
You okay?
[all breathing heavily]
- You okay? You okay?
- [whimpers]
[all gasping]
[all laughing]
[hopeful music playing]
[birds chirping]
Okay.
It's a vertical slab.
Uh...
Looks like some overhang.
It's probably a 5.13, 5.15.
Well, at least we're going down.
I saw the pterosaur
circling a carved structure
cut into a natural ledge.
They were crevice-nesters,
so it's an ideal spot.
Do we have to get a sample from an egg?
I suppose we could try
and get it from the parent,
but they're a flying carnivore
the size of an F-16.
Hmm. Okay.
[Kincaid] Clip him in.
Okay. [sighs]
[in French]
- You good?
- Good?
Yeah, good. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. Ah.
I mean, I have a 20-foot climbing wall
in my gym, so.
There you go.
It's exactly like climbing that.
Yeah, but 25 times in a row.
And you're 500 feet up, so, if you fall,
you die.
Okay. Well, that's unhelpful.
[chuckles] Don't worry. I got you.
[grunts]
[breathing deeply]
[tense music playing]
[grunting]
[panting]
It's fun, right?
[dinosaur chittering]
Krebs.
Check this out.
[breathing heavily]
- [screams]
- Rope, rope!
[grunting]
You're doing great.
We got another 40 feet to go.
[dinosaur roaring in distance]
Time to move.
Okay.
[grunts]
See? It's just like the gym.
[laughs softly]
C'est miraculeux.
Can you move the pitons?
I think we're gonna need
a couple minutes here.
[LeClerc] Okay, d'accord.
[Zora] What is this place?
Some kind of ancient temple?
It won't hurt the embryo.
Um, maybe we should make this quick, huh?
Not without breaking the egg sac.
You're a very impressive nerd, Henry.
[chuckles]
- What would the alternative be?
- To what?
To handing the samples over
to ParkerGenix?
We open-source it.
We give it to the whole world.
A bunch of people create the medicine,
nobody owns the patent,
everyone has access,
and tens of millions of lives are saved.
It's all of us, not some of us.
I don't make any money in that scenario.
Oh, no, you're broke as hell.
Yeah, I don't love that part.
[chuckles]
[dinosaurs snarling in distance]
[chitters]
[squawks]
[gasps]
- [dart beeps]
- I've got it.
[LeClerc] Hey, Zora! Attention!
[dinosaur chirping]
[chittering]
Uh-oh.
[squawks]
[roars]
[grunts]
[Zora] Hey!
Hey!
[squawks]
Oh, gee. [grunts]
The sample!
[growling]
[grunts] Hey!
[grunts]
[squawks]
[growling]
[groans] Oh!
Kincaid! Pull me up!
- Kincaid! Help!
- LeClerc?
[dinosaur roaring in distance]
Hey!
[groans] Kincaid! Au secours!
Krebs, pull! Pull!
Pull me up! Pull me up!
- You okay?
- Yeah. You?
Oh, shit.
[sample clatters]
Oh! Quick!
[yells]
[grunting]
Henry! [grunting]
[grunts]
[dinosaur squawks in distance]
[Kincaid] Pull! Up!
Pull me up! [screams]
Pull me! Pull me!
Kincaid!
[Zora] Henry! Henry, stop!
I nearly got it!
Henry, it's gonna snap! Stop! [grunts]
Hold on!
- Pull!
- [grunts]
- Pull! Pull!
- [growling]
Oh, shit!
LeClerc!
[screams]
[squawking]
[Krebs yells]
Come on! Here!
[Krebs] Where?
- [bellows]
- [grunting]
[both grunting]
Stop! Henry! It's gonna split!
- I've got it!
- [dart beeping]
[screams, grunts]
Oh, no.
Henry! Henry!
[yells]
[grunting]
[dinosaurs squeaking]
[gasping]
[hopeful music playing]
[Kincaid] Doc!
You okay?
[panting]
[sighs]
Let's go home.
[breathing heavily]
- [animals calling in distance]
- [insects trilling]
[animals chittering in distance]
[animals chirping, calling]
Isabella.
Honey.
Let's go.
We're almost there.
[Kincaid] I see the helipad.
It's in the middle of a reservoir.
No sign of the kids, though.
Will they even be able to find this place?
[Zora] Hey.
Hey, there's footprints here.
Hello?
Reuben.
- Teresa.
- Zora, they could be anything.
- They could be animals. It could be...
- In Nikes?
I appreciate what you're doing.
I really do.
- But we are in a crunch right now.
- Hello?
And we don't even know
if they survived the rocks.
- Reuben. Teresa.
- The helicopter's coming.
Well, we'll just have the pilots
do a low pass over the whole island
while there's still light.
- That is an incredibly dangerous idea.
- Well, nobody asked you.
Hello?
[Kincaid] Isabella!
[Xavier] Hello?
Hello?
Anyone, please!
[shout echoing]
[Reuben] Hello?
[Teresa] Is anyone here?
[Zora] Hey!
Oh, my God! You made it!
- Oh, God. Oh, my God.
- Hi.
You okay?
- Thank God you're alive.
- Where is he?
- No, no, no. Where is that son of a bitch?
- What? Who?
- That guy! He let me fall.
- Yeah, he tried to kill her.
Wait, wait. Who let you fall?
Hey, Krebs.
- I'm gonna kill him!
- [Kincaid] Hey, hey.
- [Reuben] He's got a gun, Teresa! No!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Let's just settle down, everybody. Okay?
[Teresa] You stopped me calling for help.
You wanted me to die.
What are you talking about?
I tried to catch you.
[scoffs] No, no, no. You looked
right at me and you let me fall!
She's lying.
[scoffs]
If she's lying,
then why do you have a gun?
Because she's hysterical.
[Teresa chuckles]
No, I'm not hysterical. I'm homicidal!
- Hey, whoa, whoa.
- Teresa, no!
[Kincaid] Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, hey.
- Don't rush the guy with the gun.
- Enough.
Whoa. All right. All right.
Yes, everybody just relax.
Why don't I take that?
It looks heavy.
And...
I'll keep it safe with me.
- [clears throat]
- [handcuffs click]
Now, we're all just gonna relax
and wait here
for the helicopter to arrive.
There's a helicopter coming?
Any minute.
We just gotta make sure they see us.
[Reuben] Told you we'd made it.
Then we all get on the helicopter
and we forget any ridiculous stories
about whatever she said.
- [Zora] I think we all need to...
- Stop talking! Stop talking.
[mechanical creaking in distance]
[mechanical whirring]
It's the generator.
It must be on a timer.
[dinosaur roars]
The generator sounds angry.
Maybe this place is deserted
in the daytime.
But not so deserted at night?
[electricity powering up]
["Stand by Me" playing on speakers]
[echoing] ♪ And the land is dark ♪
♪ And the moon is the only ♪
♪ Light we'll see ♪
It's okay, honey. It's okay.
♪ Be afraid ♪
♪ Oh, I won't be afraid ♪
♪ Just as long ♪
♪ As you stand ♪
♪ Stand by me... ♪
[roars]
[squawks]
Oh, not that thing.
[snarling]
[roaring]
[Zora] Run!
[dramatic music playing]
[Zora] Split up!
[Teresa] Go. Go, go, go.
[roaring]
[Xavier] Reuben!
[Reuben] Teresa, get the rack!
[Teresa] What are they?
[Xavier] I don't know,
but they're mutant as shit!
[Reuben] Come on, get to the back!
- [banging on door]
- [Dolores chittering]
[snarling]
[banging on door]
- [breathing heavily]
- [electricity whirring softly]
The hell is this place?
It's a lab. Cross-breeding, mutations.
It's where it all happened.
- [snarling]
- [banging on door]
[panting]
[grunting]
[shrieks]
[Zora grunting] Stop!
You're missing it!
- Give me the gun!
- Get off me!
[screams]
[grunts, groans]
[vehicle creaking]
- [breathing heavily]
- [Dolores chittering]
Dolores!
[Teresa whispering] Bella!
[Isabella] You found us.
[Teresa] Bella.
[toy dinosaur] Show me candy!
I'm gonna eat you all up.
- [Dolores whimpering]
- It's okay.
[Teresa] Bella!
- [squawks]
- [Teresa] Bella!
[gasps]
[toy dinosaur] Show me candy!
I'm gonna eat you all up.
[distorted] Show me candy!
[grunts sharply]
I'm gonna eat you all up.
[can rattles]
[whimpering]
[roars]
- [object clatters]
- [grunting]
[whimpering]
[hissing]
- [whispering] Come on. Come on.
- [bottle rolling]
[hissing]
[panting softly]
[tense music playing]
[roars]
[sniffs]
[grunting]
That way. Go, go, go. Give me that.
[Kincaid] Hey. There's a tunnel system.
It goes under the whole island.
[clattering in distance]
[gasps]
[Kincaid] The tunnel leads to the ocean.
There's a boat.
[helicopter whirring in distance]
[Loomis] It's the helicopter.
I'll get the kids.
You get the pilot's attention.
Don't let 'em leave, doc!
Don't let 'em leave!
[dinosaur growling]
[heavy footstep]
- [dinosaur growling]
- [heavy footsteps approaching]
[deep growling]
[dramatic music playing]
I can't see anyone.
Okay. We circle for two minutes,
then get the hell out.
[breathing heavily]
[roaring]
[growling]
[panting]
- [dinosaur roars]
- [vehicle clanks heavily]
- [engine starts]
- [car alarm blaring]
[roaring]
[grunting]
[automated voice]
Caution. Pedestrian ahead.
- [roars]
- [car alarm continues blaring]
[tires squealing]
Shit.
- [car alarm fading in distance]
- [panting]
[squawks]
[sniffing]
[Reuben, muffled] Down the tunnel.
Quick. Go, go, go, go, go.
That way, go!
[Teresa] It's okay. It's okay, Bella.
[snarling]
[sniffs]
[grunting sharply]
[Xavier] Come on, come on, come on!
- You okay?
- [Teresa] Which way do we go?
[Reuben] To the left. Hurry!
- Go.
- [Isabella] I'm scared.
Okay, I'm gonna call it.
Let's head home.
[Loomis] Hey!
Stop!
Hey!
Down here!
Come back!
[pilot 1] Wait!
There. Seven o'clock, low.
[pilot 2] I see it! Combing left.
[sighs]
Oh, thank God.
Come on.
[panting]
Duncan!
They're coming back!
- [metallic creaking]
- [low growling]
Hey!
- Quick! Down here!
- [helicopter blades whining]
- [growling]
- Oh, no!
No, no, no!
[all screaming]
[Kincaid] Loomis.
[Reuben] Kincaid, is that you?
- Reuben!
- [Teresa] Hello?
Where are you guys?
- [Xavier] Hey! Hey! Down here! Hey! Hey!
- [Reuben] Here! Hey!
[Kincaid] Oh, thank God.
[Teresa] Get us out of here!
Wait, wait, wait.
Just wait... Wait, wait, wait.
- Whoa, whoa!
- [panting] Did you...
- Did you see that thing?
- Get inside! Get inside!
Okay, listen up.
- This is a drainage tunnel.
- [snarling in distance]
Leads down to the sea.
There's a dock
with a boat hanging on it. I saw it.
What about the helicopter?
No helicopter.
- What?
- No.
Wait. But what if the boat doesn't work?
Hey. I'm not gonna let you get hurt, okay?
All right. Come on.
This way. Let's get to the dock.
[car alarm blaring]
[dramatic music playing]
Shut up!
[automated voice]
Caution. Pedestrian ahead.
[dinosaur grumbles]
[grunting]
[car alarm continues blaring]
[dinosaur growls]
- [Reuben] Down the tunnel. Quick.
- [gasps]
[Isabella] I don't think
this is the right way, Dad.
[Reuben] Yeah, come on. Go, go.
[Teresa] Zora!
- [screams]
- [dinosaur shrieks]
[gun clicking empty]
- [wheezes]
- Go!
- [Loomis] Are you okay?
- Go! Go!
Krebs took the jeep.
[Kincaid] If he gets to the boat
before us, he'll take that too.
Come on, Z, we gotta go!
[Loomis] There's the ocean! Up there!
- I see the boat. It's that way.
- [Kincaid] How do we open the gate?
[Reuben] It's there, it's there.
The control panel.
[Xavier] I'll go. I'll go.
- Can you fit through?
- [grunts] I'm trying, I'm trying!
Shit. [grunts]
[dinosaur roars]
[Xavier] Maybe we can lift it.
[dinosaur hissing]
- Guys? That thing is back!
- [others grunting]
[Zora] Again! All together, lift.
One, two, three... [grunts]
[all straining]
- Hey. Hey!
- [Xavier] Hey, hey, hey. Isabella.
- No, no, no.
- Bella! Bella, wait!
- Bella!
- Come back here! Come here!
[Loomis] Careful, Bella! Be careful!
[Kincaid] Isabella! Find the power button.
[chitters]
[frantic snorting]
[growling]
Hurry, we have to open the gate!
It's coming!
- Hey!
- [overlapping shouts]
- Bella, open the gate!
[grunting]
[roaring]
[growling]
[car alarm approaching]
[automated voice] Excess speed. Slow down.
Caution. Pedestrian ahead.
[roaring]
- [car alarm distorts, stops]
- [grunting]
[Kincaid] Go, go, go!
[Krebs whimpering]
[snarling]
Come on. We gotta go. We gotta go.
- Teresa, come on!
- Come on.
[squawks]
- [Kincaid] Now, Z, now!
- [roars]
[dinosaur hissing]
[grunting]
[grunts]
- [growling]
- [pained grunting]
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
[crying]
[screams]
[grunts]
[Reuben] Hurry.
The hoist control's over there. Go.
[Xavier] How do you get the boat down?
- [Zora] Lower the boat.
- Where's the power?
- [Zora] Here, take this!
- I got it. I got it.
- [Xavier] Turn it on.
- [alarm blaring]
[Reuben] The hoist is broken. It's jammed!
[Xavier] Come on, come on!
[branches snapping]
[growling]
[Isabella screams]
[Isabella whimpers]
[Reuben] Bella!
Don't move, honey!
[whimpering]
[breathing heavily]
[growling]
It's attracted to light. Turn it off!
Turn it off!
- Give me the flares.
- What the hell are you doing?
I've got it. I've got it. Go!
- No, no, no! What the hell are you doing?
- Hey!
- [growling]
- Right here!
You want me?
- Come on!
- [roaring]
- [Kincaid] Come on!
- No.
Duncan.
This way. Hey.
Get your sister. Get your sister!
[Kincaid] Get out of here! Go!
[poignant music playing]
Come here! This way!
- Come on!
- Duncan! Duncan!
[Kincaid] Hey!
Come on.
Don't wait, Zora! Get the kids. Go!
Come on!
[Kincaid] Save them.
[roars]
[both crying]
Come on!
[grunting]
[growling]
[laughs]
Come on!
Yeah.
[yells]
[roaring]
[chain rattling]
Go. Get in the boat. Get in the boat.
- Take the helm. Take the helm.
- [Reuben] Grab her, grab her, grab her.
- There's no power. Check the power!
- Zora!
[Zora] Duncan!
- Duncan!
- [Loomis] Zora, come on.
[Zora] Duncan!
- We have to go. Come on.
- [dinosaur roars]
[Isabella] Dad, hurry!
- [Loomis] Let's go. Come on!
- Dad, hurry!
- I'm trying! I'm trying!
- [Loomis] Go, go, go, go, go!
- [dinosaur growling]
- Hurry!
- I'm trying!
[dinosaur growling]
Dad, hurry!
- Reuben! Reuben!
- You got it.
Come on, please! Hurry!
- [engine starts]
- Go! Go, push it!
[roaring]
[Zora] Kincaid?
Duncan!
[panting]
[sobbing softly]
[gasps] Dad.
Hey! Hey!
[hopeful music playing]
[Zora] Turn the boat around!
There he is. I see him!
[Teresa] There!
Yeah, there! Go!
Hey!
[laughs]
[pensive music playing]
Who do we give it to?
You decide.
We'll give it to everyone.
Look.
[sweeping music playing]
[hopeful music playing]
[adventurous music playing]
[gentle music playing]
[tense music playing]
[hopeful music playing]
- [music ends]
- [birds chirping]